回到我们的承诺服务器模块，我们会出来
back in our pledge server module we'll come in out
立即创建承诺和最近的承诺
create pledge and recent pledges for now
我们稍后再讨论这些
we'll come back to these later
但现在我们想从循环开始
but for now we want to start with the loop
我要把它放在最上面
I'm going to put that right up at the top here
我们需要一个不断接收和接收的函数
and we need a function that continuously receives and
处理消息
handles messages
在无限循环中
in an endless loop
所以我们只调用那个函数listen loop
so we'll just call that function listen loop
你可以随心所欲地称呼它
you can call this whatever you want
然后我们将开始打印
and then we'll start off by printing out
等待消息
waiting for a message
然后我们需要接收块
and then we need to receive block
所以当调用监听循环时
so when listen loop is called
它转身接听电话
it turns around and calls receive
这将阻止
which will block
暂停进程
suspend the process
等待匹配的消息
waiting for a matching message
到达进程的邮箱
to arrive in the process's mailbox
但要记住
but remember
接收只处理邮箱中的一封邮件
receive only processes one message in the mailbox
所以要处理多个消息
so to handle more than one message
收到消息后我们需要循环回
after receiving a message we need to loop back
最多接收
up to receive
所以服务器进程可以等待下一条消息
so the server process can wait for the next message
并做到这一点
and to do that
我们将在这里递归地调用监听循环
we'll recursively call listen loop right here
所以我们将匹配消息然后我们将运行一些代码
so we'll match the message then we'll run some code
然后我们将在这里循环回听循环
and then we'll loop back up to listen loop here
这会说好的等待另一条消息
which is going to say okay waiting for another message
然后它将阻止此接收
and then it's going to block on this receive
等待下一条消息
waiting for the next message
好的，所以我们要处理的第一条消息
okay so the first message we want to handle
有这个图案
has this pattern
它将让原子创建承诺
it's going to have the atom create pledge
那么第二个元素将是名称
then the second element will be the name
第三个元素是
and the third element will be
数量
the amount
那么就代码而言，我们想要做的是
then in terms of the code what we want to do is
在外部服务处发送该承诺
send that pledge at the external service
所以我要把它贴在那里
so I'm just going to paste that right there
所以我们只提取名称
so we just extract the name
以及消息中的金额
and the amount from the message
穿梭其中
and shuttle those through
到将其发送到外部服务的那个函数
to that function that sends it to the external service
然后我将使用打印输出
and then I'm going to use a print out
名字承诺
name pledged
数量
the amount
然后我们循环回听循环
and then we loop back up to listen loop
现在我们还想将质押添加到本地现金中
now we also want to add the pledge to the local cash
这将是服务器进程存储的状态
which will be the state stored by the server process
好吧，我们想这样做
well we want to do that
在我们将其发送到外部服务之后
right after we've sent it to the external service
我们的现金将成为灵丹妙药
and our cash is going to be an elixir list
我要说现金
I'm going to say cash
这是清单
here's the list
然后列表的每个元素都是一个元组
and then each element of the list is a tuple
所以这将是名字
so it'll be the name
以及质押金额
and the amount of the pledge
但这每次都会创造新的现金
but this is going to create a new cash each time
通过这个监听循环
through this listen loop
因为
because
这只是我们在这里分配的一个局部变量
this is just a local variable that we assign to here
所以我们需要
so instead we need to
记住现金并添加到每个
remember the cash and add to it each
通过循环的时间
time through the loop
因为我们希望承诺最终出现在一个列表中
because we want the pledges to end up in a single list
换句话说，我们需要服务器进程
in other words we need the server process
将现金保持为内部状态
to maintain the cash as internal state
现在
now
当我们解析 http 标头时，我们学会了如何做到这一点
we learned how to do that when we parsed http headers
在课程的早期
earlier on in the course
我们只需要传递状态
we just need to pass the state which
在这种情况下是一个列表
is a list in this case
作为这个监听循环递归函数的参数
as an argument to this listen loop recursive function
现在而不是调用这个现金
now rather than calling this cash
我要把它改成新的
I'm going to change it to be new
下划线状态
underscore state
所以我们设置了新的状态，然后我们用它重复
so we set the new state and then we recurs with it
现在让它工作
now for that to work
我们需要改变这个监听循环
we need to change this listen loop
以状态为论据
to take the state as an argument
我将称之为一个状态
and I'm going to call this one state
所以一些状态会被传递到监听循环中
so some states going to get passed into the listen loop
然后在这里
and then down here
当我们创造现金时
when we're creating the cash
我们要做的是把这个名字和数量元组
what we want to do is put this name and amount tuple
作为列表状态的负责人
as the head of the list state
所以我们在这里使用 cons 运算符
so we're using the cons operator here
这个承诺将被添加为头部
and this pledge is going to get added as the head
这份清单是我们的州
of this list which is our state
这会给我们一个新的清单
that's going to give us a new list
我们将分配给新状态
which we're going to assign to new state
然后我们再重复一遍
and then we recurs with that
哪个
which
将成为在监听中传递的值
will become the value that gets passed in the listen
循环，下一个质押将成为头部
loop and the next pledge will become the head
那个新的状态
of that new state
现在暂时看看新的状态
now for now to see the new state
我们将它打印到屏幕上
we'll print it to the screen
所以就在我打印出坐骑的名字之后
so just after I print out the name of the mount
我们将打印出来
we'll print out
新状态是
new state is
然后我们将调用检查
and then we'll call inspect
关于新状态
on the new state
所以现在我们有了这个
so now that we have this
听循环功能
listen loop function
在无限循环中接收和处理消息
that receives and handles messages in an endless loop
我们可以生成一个运行该函数的进程
we can spawn a process that run that function
现在我们
for now we
只是想试验一下这个服务器进程
just want to experiment with this server process
我们稍后实际上会将它连接到我们的控制器
we'll actually hook it up later to our controller
所以让我们在 if 中生成它
so let's just spawn it in if
我们知道怎么做
we know how to do that
我们只叫 spawn
we just call spawn
我们将给它我们的模块调查承诺服务器
we're going to give it our module survey pledge server
然后是我们要运行的函数的名称
then the name of the function we wanted to run
它被称为监听循环
it's called listen loop
然后第三个参数是
and then the third argument is
要发送的参数列表
a list of arguments to send
到那个函数或传递给那个函数
to that function or to pass to that function
记住监听循环采用初始状态
remember listen loop takes the initial state
我们希望初始状态是一个空列表
we want the initial state to be an empty list
所以我们将在那里传递一个空列表
so we're going to pass in an empty list there
所以我们有一个清单
so we've got a list
里面有一个空列表
that has an empty list inside of it
并且进程正在等待消息
and the process is waiting for a message
我们看到坑是一六十五
we see the pit is one sixty five
现在还记得我们在 ix 会话中的时候
now remember when we're in an ix session
我们已经在一个过程中
we're already in a process
现在我们要向邮箱发送消息
and now we want to send a message to the mailbox
衍生的服务器进程
of the spawned server process
所以你可以把 ix 会话想象成一个
so you can think of the ix session like a
客户端进程
client process
所以要向我们调用 send 的服务器发送消息
so to send a message to the server where we call send
然后我们给它服务器的坑
and then we give it the pit of the server
然后我们给它我们想要发送的信息
and then we give it the message we want to send
看起来像这样
looks like this
创建承诺
create pledge
我们要说拉里
we're going to say larry
是名字和 $10
is the name and $10
现在你注意到我没有在这里使用括号
now you notice I didn't use parentheses right here
sin是一个函数
sin is a function
你可以在那里使用假肢
and you can use prostheses right there
但我认为移除假肢
but I think removing the prostheses
它只是说清楚
it just makes it clear
这两个参数在做什么，所以它是一个 pid
what those two arguments are doing so it's a pid
然后是一条消息，以便您可以以任何您想要的方式执行此操作
and then a message so you can do this any way you want
我现在就用这种风格
I'm just going to use this style for now
很酷，消息已收到
cool the message was received
我们看到了我们所拥有的争议的结果
we see the output of that disputes that we had
在听循环
in listen loop
我们还看到我们的新状态是一个列表
we also see that our new state is a list
与元组 larry 和 tin
with the tuple larry and tin
然后你也看到这个东西印在这里
and then you also see this thing printed right here
这是消息
which is the message
而这个 sin 函数
while this sin function
总是返回已发送的消息
always returns the message that was sent
这就是为什么我们看到这个
which is why we see this
在 ix 中，因为它总是打印出来
in ix because it always prints out
您刚刚调用的函数的返回
the return of the function that you just called
然后我们的监听循环重新返回
and then our listen loop re back
自己等待下一条消息
on itself to wait for the next message
这就是为什么我们看到等待消息
which is why we see waiting for message
所以 10 美元不会让我们非常满意
so $10 isn't going to get us very
远在我们的鳄鱼承诺驱动器上
far on our crocodile pledge drive
所以让我们创建另一个承诺
so let's create another pledge
假设 mo 给了我们 20 美元
let's say mo gives us $20
好的，我们看到状态已更新，我们的现金现在有
okay we see the state was updated our cash now has
莫以 20 美元排在榜首，然后
mo at the head of the list with $20 and then
拉里是列表中的第二个
larry is the second one in the list
现在你可能会注意到我点击返回的时候
now you probably notice when I hit return there
那森并没有阻止等待响应
that sen didn't block waiting for a response
它只是将消息放入
it simply puts the message in the
服务器进程作为邮箱
server process as mailbox
然后几乎立即返回
and then returns almost immediately
所以我们可以继续做其他事情
so we can carry on doing other things
而服务器进程处理消息
while the server process handles the message
只记得发送消息是
just remember sending a message is
总是异步操作
always an asynchronous operation
curly想要参与第二个动作
curly wants to get in on the action two
所以他会给我们30块钱
so he's going to give us 30 bucks
现在很酷，我们的现金有三个承诺
cool now our cash has three pledges
并且 curly 位于列表的首位
and curly is at the head of the list
所以因为监听循环是一个递归循环
so because listen loop is a recursive loop
生成过程永远不会终止
the spawn process never terminates
它连续运行接收和处理消息
it runs continuously receiving and handling messages
我们现在看到它正在等待下一条消息
and we see right now it's waiting for the next message
现在你可能会担心这个递归
now you might be concerned that this recursive
循环会浪费一堆 cpu 周期
loop would waste a bunch of cpu cycles
但大多数时候
but most of the time
该过程被阻止而不被欺骗
the process is blocked undeceived
所以调度程序
and so the scheduler
抢占或暂停阻塞进程
preempts or suspends the block process
所以它不会对cpu征税
so it doesn't tax the cpu
到目前为止，我们只有三个承诺
we only have three pledges so far
所以我们真的
so we really
不必担心只保留最
don't have to worry about keeping just the most
最近的承诺
recent pledges
但我们稍后会谈到
but we'll get to that later
虽然现在
for now though
而不是服务器进程
instead of the server process
只需将现金打印到屏幕上
simply printing the cash to screen
我们想要这里的 ix 客户端进程
we want the client process which is ix right here
能够以现金获得承诺
to be able to get the pledges in the cash
为此，客户将发送一个
to do that the client will send a
服务器需要处理的不同消息
different message that the server needs to handle
接收可以处理各种
receive can handle various
使用模式匹配壁橱的消息
messages using pattern matching closets
类似于 case 表达式
similar to a case expression
所以我们可以在这里添加一个新模式
so we can just add a new pattern right here
消息将看起来像最近的承诺
the message is going to look like this recent pledges
它只是一个原子，没有元组
it's just an atom there's no tuple
当它收到这条消息时
when it receives this message
它需要当前状态的现金
it needs this in the cash which is the current state
使用 send 返回客户端进程
back to the client process using send
当我们寄回现金时
and when we send back the cash
我们将它包装在一个看起来像这样的消息中
we'll wrap it in a message that looks like this
我们只会得到原子响应
we'll just have the atom response
然后我们需要发回状态
and then we need to send back the state
现在您可以将状态作为消息发回
now you could just send back the state as the message
但是我们
but we
将其标记为响应只是为了减少歧义
tagged it as response just to make it less ambiguous
然后最后
and then finally
虽然处理这个
although handling this
消息不更新状态
message doesn't update the state
它仍然需要与当前环回
it still needs to loop back with the current
未修改的未修改状态
unmodified unchanged state
因为我们这里没有改变状态
because we haven't changed the state here
我们只是把它传回去
we just pass it back through
只有一个问题
there's just one problem
什么是猪
what's the pig
好吧，这是客户端进程的坑
well it's the pit of the client process
那是要求他们最近的承诺
that's asking for their recent pledges
服务器进程需要知道的坑
the server process needs to know the pit
客户端进程
of the client process
为了发回承诺
in order to send the pledges back
记住它
to it and remember
进程只能通过消息进行通信
processes can only communicate via messages
所以发送这个消息的客户端进程
so the client process that sends this message
必须在该消息中包含其 pid
must include its pid in that message
所以我们会让客户端进程发送它的pid
so we'll have the client process send its pid
作为消息中的第一个元素
as the first element in the message
我们将把它变成一个元组
we'll make this a tuple
然后第一个元素将调用 sender
and then the first element will call sender
然后是消息中的第一个元素
and then whatever that first element is in the message
会被束缚
will be bound
到这个变量发件人
to this variable sender
现在
now
这不一定是元组中的第一个元素
this doesn't have to be the first element in the tuple
但是发件人通常是第一个元素
but it's common for the sender to be the first element
所以我们要坚持这个成语
so we're going to stick with that idiom
你可以把它想象成回报
you can think of it like the return
消息发送者的地址
address of the message sender
它在说嘿
it's saying hey
给我回复
send me the reply
然后我们可以使用 sender 发送消息
then we can use the sender to send a message
回到那个客户进程
back to that client process
只是想看看发生了什么
and just to see what's happening
我们会将发件人打印到屏幕上
we'll print the sender to the screen
所以我只会说气味承诺
so I'll just say scent pledges to
然后我会检查中心
and then I'll inspect the center
所以现在我们有两种模式
so now we have two patterns
这意味着接收将等待消息
which means receive will wait for a message
匹配任何这些模式
that matches any of those patterns
和案例一样
and just as with case
从上到下的消息或模式匹配
messages or pattern match from top to bottom
第一个匹配的模式有
and the first pattern that matches has
其相关的代码块执行
its associated block of code executed
好的，让我们在 ix 中试一试
okay let's give this a whirl in ix
我只是要重新加载
I'm just going to reload the
服务器模块，因为我们改变了它
server module since we changed that
那我就清理一下
then I'm just going to clean that up
现在我们可以继续重生
and now we can go ahead and respawn
我们的质押服务器监听循环
our pledge server listen loop
我们将为拉里创建一个承诺
we'll create a pledge for larry
有一个给莫
there's one for mo
最后是卷曲的
and finally there's curly
现在在以后的某个时间
now at some later time
我们想得到最近的承诺
we want to get the recent pledges
所以我们需要发送
so we can need to send
给我们的服务器进程的消息
a message to our server process
并且消息有两个元素记住
and the message has two elements remember
第一个是过程的坑
the first one is the pit of the process
服务器应该
that the server should
将响应发送回
send the response back to
好吧，我们想将响应发送回
well we wanted to send response back to
这个过程 ix 过程
this process the ix process
我们可以通过使用 self
we can get that by using self
然后是消息的第二个元素
and then the second element of the message
就是这个原子
is just this atom
最近的承诺
recent pledges
好的
okay
我们看到服务器发送承诺的输出
we see the output that the server sent the pledges to
pid 一六十三
pid one sixty three
这是我们的 ix 进程 ID
that's our ix process id
所以让我们在我们的邮箱中选择我们使用该信息功能
so let's pick in our mailbox we use that info function
坑是自我的，我们想要信息
the pit is self and we want the info
我们想看消息
we want to see the messages
果然我们有消息
and sure enough we have a message
标记响应，这是我们的承诺清单
tag response and it's a list of our pledges
现在
now that
让我们看看邮箱里的消息
just let us peek at the messages in the mailbox to
实际收到消息
actually receive the messages
从客户的邮箱
from the client's mailbox
我们需要调用接收
we need to call receive
从客户端进程
from the client process
我们在客户进程中
and we're in the client process
因为我们在分裂中
because we're in the secession
所以收到我们想要匹配的模式是响应
so receive due the pattern we want to match is response
然后我们将绑定这个地方的任何值
and then we'll bind whatever value is at this place
在消息中作为承诺
in the message as pledges
你可以随便叫它
you can call that whatever you want
然后我们将提取它并返回它
and then we're just going to extract that and return it
作为接收语句的返回
as the return of the receive statement
我们回到承诺清单
and we get back to the list of pledges
现在我们使用 ix 作为客户端进程
now we use ix as the client process
只是为了试验服务器
just to experiment with the server
但最终是客户端进程
but ultimately the client process
将是一个请求处理过程
will be a request handling process
从我们的网络服务器产生的
that spawn from our web server
所以当我们收到一个关于承诺的帖子请求时
so when we get a post request for pledges
这个函数将被运行
this function is going to be run
在请求处理过程中
in the request handling process
所以这将是客户端进程
so it's going to be the client process
呼吁创造承诺
that calls create pledge
如果我们收到最近承诺的获取请求
and if we get a get request for recent pledges
然后这个函数将运行
then this function is going to run
在请求处理过程中
in a request handling process
所以它将是调用的客户端进程
so it's going to be the client process that calls
最近的承诺
recent pledges
为此，我们需要实施这些
for this to work we need to implement these
两个函数创建质押和最近质押
two functions create pledge and recent pledges